[tense music]
[helicopter whirring]
[pilot 1] Command, this is Coyote Six.
We're 70 miles northwest of the base.
Altitude, 1,500 feet.
Requesting clearance for landing.
[woman] Coyote Six, this is Command.
You're cleared to land on Runway Three.
Wind, 50 at 14 knots,
maximum two-niner-seven-four inches,
watch for chop.
[loud bang]
[pilot 2] Mayday! We're hit!
-Losing altitude.
-Shit.
[helicopter wheezing, squeaking]
Command, this is Mad Dogs.
We have visual on Alpha Two,
and it's going down.
Coordinates 4-2 Sierra Whiskey
Alpha-niner-4-6-5-0-6-7-niner-2-niner.
[man] Tell the other units to stand by.
Team Three, Team Six,
this is Command. Stand by.
Wait, what?
[woman] I repeat,
Team Three and Team Six,
-stand by and wait for orders.
-Take us down! We're gonna check it out.
[tense music]
[woman] Sir, the militia's
converging on the crash site.
[man 1] Alpha Two's under attack.
They're totally surrounded.
[indistinct chatter]
[tense music continues]
[pilot 3] Command, got eyes on Alpha Two.
Preparing to engage.
[woman] Negative.
You are to stand by. Do not engage.
-[man 1] They're firing on the enemy.
-[man 2] What unit is that?
[woman] Mad Dogs, sir.
Goddammit. Tell them to stand down
and get back in formation!
Command to Mad Dogs. Stand down,
-return to formation!
-When we hit the deck,
we light 'em up with the SAWs,
then we go for survivors. Got it?
[rapid exhaling in unison]
[man 1] Command to Mad Dogs,
stand down and return to formation!
-[helicopter whirring]
-[rope squeaks]
[guns firing]
-[guns firing]
-[blood splatters]
-[MD 1] Clear!
-[MD 2] Bastards took our guys!
[eerie music]
-[MD 3] Fuck.
-[MD 1] One here.
[men grunting]
[man] US Army Mad Dogs, can you move?
Oh, shit.
-[tires screech]
-[man grunting]
Okay. He's still alive.
-[loud explosion]
-[men groaning]
[crowd yelling, cheering]
[ominous music]
[fire crackling]
[soft thudding]
[liquid pouring]
[metal clangs]
[men yelling]
[metal clanging]
[aggressive yells]
[theme music plays]
-[child coughing]
-[indistinct chatters]
[woman] Hey.
I'm Claire.
Claire Redfield.
What's your name?
Remotsu…
Ganape?
Okay. Guess I'm gonna have
to learn the language a little better.
[staff 1] No, Ms. Claire.
This child is mute.
He cannot speak.
What?
He was in the civil war.
He cannot speak.
[distressed sigh]
[Claire] Oh, man.
The things you've probably seen.
Well…
if you're here…
then you're safe.
I'll make sure of it.
[Claire] Do you like to draw?
[grumbles]
[Claire] Can I see?
[light chuckle]
[Claire groans]
[haunting music]
Oh, my God.
Did you see this?
[sighs]
[haunting music continues]
[operator] Delta, Charlie, 2-0-2-1-7,
this is the Ace of Spades.
You're cleared to land on Runway 0-1.
Wind, 30 at five knots.
[heels clacking]
[knocks on door]
Thirty minutes should do.
The President's scheduled…
[exhales]
…an emergency call from a congressman.
[man] I'm sure that can wait till later.
You're the third agent?
Where's the fourth?
There's supposed to be four of us.
Leon should be on his way.
[groans] Leon?
Leon, as in the guy who saved
the President's daughter?
Yep.
That Leon. He's more than qualified.
[man] Qualified? [scoffs]
More like lucky.
The only reason he's the golden boy now
is because he was
in the wrong place at the right time.
He successfully handled
dozens of critical missions.
In fact, he's on his way here
from that terror attack in Pittsburgh.
-Like I said--
-In this line of work,
luck doesn't solve problems.
Skills do.
[light claps]
The President's ready. Come on.
[man sighs]
It's an honor to be working
with the hero of Penamstan.
Hero?
Yeah.
[pilot 4] Copy. Runway 01.
Wind, 30 at five knots.
Never gotten clearance
to land that fast before.
You must be special.
[helicopter whirring]
[man] Unauthorized access?
Right. Someone was trying
to get confidential files
pertaining to the President.
[guard] Presidential Aide Ryan
and three agents
have just entered the Oval Office.
Roger that. How's the West Wing look?
All's well, sir.
Thank you for waiting, gentlemen.
One agent is still en route, but these
three are probably the most qualified--
Please. Let's get this started.
Defense Secretary Wilson?
Yesterday, we received an alert
that one of our servers was compromised.
It contains
the Pentagon's military secrets
and other files that are
highly sensitive in nature.
Normally, an authorization code
from the President is required to log on.
But, somehow, they bypassed that step.
Why is top-secret data
on a server with outside access?
It can't be accessed externally.
The server's on
a 100 percent local network.
Then it was an inside job.
We've looked through all
the surveillance footage from every angle.
[sighs]
We haven't locked down any suspects yet.
So until we do, everyone who entered
or left the White House in the 24 hours
before or after the hack is a suspect.
[heavy sigh]
Guess that rules us three out.
We'd like you to find and apprehend
the person who broke into the server.
I suppose we should start by having
a look at the surveillance footage.
That'll take days.
We should get someone else to do that.
[Wilson] Actually, I have my suspicions.
Oh, god, not this again.
China has been waging a cyberwar
against this country for years now.
Putting our government, our military,
and our citizens all at risk.
-The internet is only the first stage.
-Secretary.
Making blind assumptions
will only make things worse.
We don't know it was them.
We don't know anything yet.
Hundreds of people
come and go here every day.
You and your family, Mr. President.
The staff, dignitaries, tours.
-Even the gardeners. It could be anybody--
-[power shuts down]
[Ryan] What's going on?
-[hard thump on door]
-[all gasping in surprise]
-[agent 1] Quiet!
-[agent 2] Everyone down!
[agent 1] Longhorn's secure.
Bring the Beast around.
[radio clicks]
-[beeping]
-[guard] What the hell?
Why isn't the backup power coming on?
Even if we go manual,
we can only get the emergency lights.
-Check it now.
-Must've been a surge.
-This is the chief. What's going on?
-East Wing's gone dark!
-Does anyone copy?
-[beeping]
[Ryan] Does anyone know
what's happening here?
[Jason] This is no accident.
I'm going to take a look outside.
-Patrick, with me.
-[Patrick] Roger that.
[flashlight clicks]
[retreating footsteps]
[Patrick] Everybody, stay calm!
Get back to your offices,
lock the doors, and stand by.
[uneasy music playing]
[flashlight clicking]
[man groaning in pain]
-[man groans]
-[flashlight clicks]
[Patrick] Press Secretary Spacer!
What happened?
[Spacer] I don't know.
It got dark and I…
I got hit from behind.
[Patrick] Did you see who it was?
Did they take anything?
No.
[Patrick]
I've got Press Secretary Spacer with me.
He's injured.
He's got a head wound, but he's conscious.
He says he was attacked.
-[Jason] What's going on?
-[Patrick] Somebody hit him.
I've got to take care of that wound.
-Get to it. I'm checking upstairs.
-[Patrick] Right.
[Spacer groaning]
Mr. Spacer. Mr. Spacer, sir!
What's wrong?
[ominous music]
Secretary Spacer's
going into cardiac arrest.
[Patrick] I'm getting the AED.
[thudding]
[case opens]
[tense music plays]
-[Spacer snarls]
-Mr. Spacer?
-[Spacer snarling]
-[bones crack]
-[hard thump]
-[Patrick grunts]
[Spacer snarls]
Stand down, or I'll shoot!
[Spacer growling]
-[chandelier chiming]
-[Patrick panting]
-[cord snaps]
-[loud thud]
[gunshots]
-[gunshot]
-[blood splatters]
[Patrick panting]
Leon?
Shoot them in the head. That stops them.
Come on.
[Jason] SWAT's en route.
They can deal with the zombies up here
and getting the power back up.
We'll head to the bunker.
-[Graham] Are they really zombies?
-[Leon] Yes, sir.
Sorry, I didn't get here sooner.
Not at all. I'm indebted to you
for getting my daughter, Ashley, back.
Besides, with you here,
we just might survive this.
[Graham] I never thought what happened
at Raccoon City could happen here.
[Jason] We all ready?
[Jason] Let's get the President
to the bunker. Stay sharp out there.
-[agent 3] Come on, sir.
-[Graham grunting]
[zombies growling]
[guns firing]
[Leon] Why are they here?
[digital beeping]
[hums, clanks]
Patrick, stay with the President.
Leon, Shen May, with me.
[Jason] I'm counting
on those skills of yours.
Hey.
You good?
Ye-- Yeah.
I'm just a little freaked out.
I've never seen…
zombies before.
Thanks for back there.
Okay.
[Jason] Anything even
remotely hostile gets a headshot.
[tense music]
Whatever you do,
don't let them reach the bunker.
Understood?
[Shen May] Right.
[thrilling music playing]
[zombies growling in distance]
[gun firing]
[door squeaks]
[eerie music]
[flashlight clicks]
[focused breathing]
[eerie music continues]
-[growls]
-[gun firing]
-[blood splatters]
-[body thuds]
[suspenseful music]
[gasps]
[dramatic music plays]
[flashlight clicks]
-[gunshot]
-[body thuds]
[rapid gunfire]
[zombie growling]
[gun firing continues]
Rest in peace, assholes.
[helicopter whirring]
[indistinct chatter]
[zipper rasps]
[Leon] Think it's the T-Virus?
We won't know till the lab checks it out.
More important question is,
how the hell did zombies
get in the White House?
Hmm.
And who's behind it?
-[indistinct chatter]
-[Claire groans]
Uh, Mr. Ryan, I work with TerraSave,
the NGO assisting the Penamstanis.
Do you have a moment?
What is it?
I can't find Press Secretary Spacer.
Do you know where he might be?
-Eh, he's on leave right now.
-"On leave"?
-But I have an appointment with him.
-[sighs]
I don't know what to tell you.
Perhaps you mixed up your dates.
He's not here.
I'm sorry, I… I have another appointment.
[scoffs]
-[hums in wonder]
-[footsteps]
Uh, Leon?
Claire?
[Leon] What're you doing here?
I'm here with reps
from Penamstan's provisional government.
Just trying to get some schools
and hospitals built.
[Leon] Penamstan?
Yeah.
The US wants a military presence there,
so there's supposed to be some sort
of signing ceremony next week.
Um, hey, actually,
could you take a look at something?
Yeah, sure. What's this?
A little boy drew them.
They're what the civil war
looked like six years ago.
[haunting music]
[Claire] Doesn't that look
a lot like Raccoon City?
I can't get anyone to go on record
about what happened there.
But after seeing those, I mean,
it's gotta be another outbreak.
-Hmm.
-Leon. Clock's ticking. Let's move.
Wait.
Isn't that the guy everyone calls
"the hero of Penamstan"?
[Leon] In the flesh.
Look, I gotta go.
Don't do anything stupid.
[Claire] Excuse me.
Hey, Leon.
That outfit doesn't suit you.
[both chuckling]
[Graham] It's the only way
to deal with this.
[Wilson] Mr. President, the DIA
finished their analysis of the hacking.
The files accessed
were classified documents regarding China.
-China.
-[Wilson] Yes.
They contained intel
on a bio-research facility in Shanghai
we had flagged for surveillance.
Bio-research facility?
I suggest we send Jason
and his team to investigate.
With your approval, of course.
Now, wait just a minute.
We don't want to provoke the Chinese.
Besides, we can't send anyone in,
without talking to DHS, the CIA, and--
[Wilson] Mr. President!
First, there was the hacking,
then this outbreak in the White House!
The White House, for God's sake!
We are under attack!
[helicopter whirring]
[pensive music]
Fine.
Set it up.
[Captain] She's a modified Virginia-class,
with an upgraded ASDS onboard.
We're going to sneak right in
under the East Sea Fleet's nose,
load your team onto the DS, and launch it.
You'll make your rendezvous
without them even knowing it.
Yes, sir, this little lady's outfitted
with stealth tech that's best-in-class.
I've been itching for an op
like this to try it out.
Remember, when we're running silent,
shut your holes.
I don't want this turning
into some global…
[heroic music playing]
[Captain] Take us out.
Make your depth one-five feet,
five-degree down bubble.
One-five feet,
five-degree down bubble. Aye, sir.
[Leon] Okay, where we at?
All right.
Our mission is to infiltrate
the bio-research facility
and seize any evidence
pertaining to the hacking
and the viral terrorist attack
at the White House.
I'll brief you further
when we get to shore.
We could just hack them.
What's the point of even going?
Sorry, champ. That's classified for now.
Details on the facility?
For now, classified.
[sighs] Time limit?
-Classified.
-"Classified." Right.
[Jason] Well, I'm going
to go check the gear.
Get some shut-eye.
-[door opens]
-Fantastic.
[door closes]
You wanna get dinner
when this is all over?
Sure, but full disclosure,
I have a young man waiting for me.
So…
So, it's classified.
[chuckles, exhales]
For now.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[Jason groaning in pain]
[syringe wheezing]
[groans]
[Jason panting]
[eerie music]
[crowd yelling, cheering]
[fire crackles]
[metal clanging]
[whimpers]
[aggressive yell]
[growling, munching]
-[fire roars]
-[man screaming]
[snarls]
[screaming]
-[flesh ripping]
-[men screaming]
[terrified scream]
[zombies growling]
[whimpering]
[zombies snarling]
-[snarling]
-[men screaming]
[zombies snarling continues]
[closing theme music playing]